So sometimes the first thing
to straighten
up in them is that they
should
be hopeful that Allah will
remove them
from this evil.
This hope, that Allah will
remove me
and begin to make efforts to
get
out of this trouble in the
ways
that the ulema will suggest.
And we have been reading in
this
book that is from the aspects
of
Husnu Zonni Billah, Allah
will help me.
Allah will provide support
for me out
of his mercy.
So I will begin the process
of
tawbah, all what he had done
in
the past.
If the tawbah is genuine,
if the tawbah is sincere,
Allah will provide me help.
He will pardon me if I repent
genuinely.
Unfortunately, some of the
people continue to
remain up on sin,
thinking that they are hoping
positively in
Allah.
If the hope with Allah is
positive,
then we must begin to take
steps
out of sin, if your hope,
if your anticipation of
goodness with Allah
is genuine.